PRAMOD KOTIPALLI







+1 (425) 200-5436

in pramodkotipalli



SUMMARY

Let's create cyborgs! / Huge advocate of Symbiotic Artificial Intelligence, user-centered design, and accessibility. / Interested in projects at the intersection of artificial intelligence, augmented reality, wearable computing, and cognitive science. / Highly-experienced with full-stack development, human-computer interaction research, UX+graphic+motion design, and startups.

EDUCATION

Stanford University

September 2019 - June 2021

Masters of Science Computer Science · 2021

Georgia Institute of Technology

August 2015 - August 2019

Bachelors of Science Computer Science · 2019 GPA: 3.91/4.00 (Faculty Honors)

Coursework: Machine Learning, Data Structures, Algorithms, Assembly & C, Object-Oriented Programming

EXPERIENCE

Space Exploration Technologies Corp. (SpaceX)

Hawethorne, CA

Software Engineering Intern

September 2017 - December 2017 · Designed, implemented, tested software solutions · Worked closely with PMs and UX designers

- Automated supply chain processes in ERP: mitigated legal risk, increased business efficiency
- Engineered SQL Server + .NET/C# backend that exposed RESTful APIs to AngularJS front-end
- Saved 1,500+ hr/yr of manual data entry · Led projects now used by all 7,000 employees

Cisco Systems

Software Engineering Intern

San Jose, CA May 2017 - August 2017

- Architected, researched, implemented test automation framework for Cisco's Cloud DVR services
- Developed load testing and analysis framework to generate HTTP traffic and collect relevant statistics
- Designed Angular JS front-end with Python RESTful API and ELK · Orchestrates Docker containers
- Saved 10+ hr/wk of manual and error-prone OS/network configuration · Increases engineer efficiency

School of Interactive Computing @ Georgia Institute of Technology

Project Lead / Undergraduate Research Assistant

January 2018 - August 2019

- Developing and analyzing Augmented Reality applications for intelligent warehouse mgmt. systems
- Researching responsiveness to notifications on head-worn displays and wearable displays
- Developing Google Glass apps and Python APIs with Prof. Thad Starner, Contextual Computing Group Undergraduate Research Assistant January 2016 - December 2016
- Developed predictive health analytics for heart disease patients with Professor James Rehg, Wall Lab
- Used MATLAB and Python to apply DSP + HMMs to on-body sensors to identify concerning behavior

School of Mechanical Engineering @ Georgia Institute of Technology

Atlanta, GA

Lead Software Engineer

January 2016 - May 2018

- Built service used by 2,500 students and judges in Georgia Tech's Capstone Design Expo.
- Integrated user feedback for highly-intuitive UX signicantly reducing user onboarding
- Collaborated through Git-centered workows with a tight feedback loop from advisers.
- Technologies used: Django, PostgreSQL, Git, jQuery, responsive HTML/CSS design.

AWARDS

Singapore

ACM International Symposium on Wearable Computers

October 2018

- Awarded for research work published to ACM International Symposium on Wearable Computers
- · Studied novel wearable RFID-based verification system for the central process of order picking in logistics

Grand Prize winner

Emory University, Atlanta, GA November 2016

HackATL

- Awarded for developing and presenting comprehensive business plan to Atlanta-area venture capitalists
- · Developed wearable tech for on-demand community help in emergency situations on college campuses

Emory University, Atlanta, GA

Microsoft Prize HackATL

November 2016

- Won 2nd place in Microsoft Prize category at HackATL, a tech startup hackathon at Emory University.
- Created hardware prototype for smart watches wearers to shake hands and connect online.

Grace Hopper Conference travel grant

Houston, TX

Google

October 2016

- 1 / 100 students awarded full scholarship to attend Grace Hopper Celebration of Women in Computing
- · Developed skills based on demonstrated interest/experience in promoting the role of women in computing

Faculty Honors Office of the Registrar Atlanta, GA 2016-2018

· Awarded to students who earn a 4.0 GPA in a full-time academic semester

Received in multiple semesters including Spring 2016, Summer 2016, Spring 2017, and Spring 2018

<gt-webdev/>

College of Computing

President, Officer, Technical Speaker

January 2016 - December 2018

Designed curriculum, lead weekly meetings, hosted one-on-one "office hours" for hundreds of students

ACTIVITIES

PUBLICATIONS

Notification perception with visual distraction on Google Glass and Smartwatches

in progress

August 2018 - present

We investigate how are notifications are perceived differently when presented on wrist-mounted displays (e.g. smartwatches) and head-worn displays (e.g. Google Glass). We formulate and execute a dual-task study paradigm pairing notification stimuli with a visual search distraction task developed by prior literature.

Augmented Reality Head Worn Display Positioning for Sparse Order-Picking

under review by ACM IMWUT

January 2018 - May 2019

Order picking forms a large part of modern logistics, accounting for up to 55% of operating costs in over 750,000 warehouses around the world that currently ship over \$1 trillion worth of goods every year. Head worn displays (HWDs) help pickers more accurately and efficiently pick items in industry, and order picking can be a good surrogate task for investigating on-the-go use of HWDs in general. We used the Magic Leap One, a binocular head worn display, to investigate four different positions in the visual field for a virtual picking display: center-center: -5° to 5° horizontally and -5° to 5° vertically, center-right: 10° to 20°horizontally and -5° to 5° vertically, bottom-center: -5° to 5° horizontally and -15° to -5° vertically, and bottom-right: 10° to 20° horizontally and -15° to -5° vertically. The goal of the study is to determine the most efficient order picking display position in an environment that requires walking to travel between the pick shelves. We found that bottom-right results insignificantly worse than or, at best, similar to other positions in terms of accuracy and users' overall preference, subjective accuracy, subjective speed, comfort, and learnability. Due to relative parity with center-center in terms of speed, accuracy, cognitive workload, and user preference, the center-right position provides the best-performing binocular display position for HWD manufacturers and warehouse order pickers while minimizing the risk of the cognitive capture observed in other studies using the center-center position.

RF-Pick: order picking using a HUD with wearable RFID verification

best paper © ACM International Symposium on Wearable Computers

January 2018 - October 2019

Order picking accounts for 55% of the annual \$60 billion spent on warehouse operations in the United States.

Reducing human-induced errors in the order fulfillment process can save warehouses and distributors significant costs. We investigate a RFID-based verification method wherein wearable RFID scanners, worn on the wrists, scan passive RFID tags mounted on an item's bin as the item is picked; this method is used in conjunction with a head-up display (HUD) to guide the user to the correct item. We compare this RFID verification method to pick-to-light with button verification, pick-to-paper with barcode verification, and pick-to-paper with no verification. We find that pick-to-HUD with RFID verification enables significantly faster picking, provides the lowest error rate, and provides the lowest task workload.

PROJECTS

UX / Graphic / Motion Designer

personal explorations in animation, graphic design, and UX research

December 2018 - present

- Designed, animated, edited, and published over 40 short videos and 20 high-quality static renders
- Demonstrates improving skills in animation, modeling, video production, sound mixing, and vector art
- Continuing to gain mastery of MAXON's Cinema 4D and Adobe's Creative Cloud products
- Portfolio continues to grow with new original work uploaded every week: https://www.instagram.com/p13i.

dARts

play darts in augmented reality

May 2018

- Designed interactive experience for collaborative darts game in augmented reality
- Used iOS frameworks like SceneKit to draw planes/objects into real-world with ARKit

MetroSync

a web app to help musicians rehearse together

May 2018

- Designed/implemented web app featuring metronome synced across devices aiding in musical practice
 Designed and said time Walk Contact have a Characteristics between Agrandar ID front and IDECT AD
- Developed real-time Web Socket-based app · Shared information between AngularJS front-end, REST API

RichCaptions

symbolic math captions for educational videos

September 2016

- Designed/implemented UX for captioning and viewing videos with LaTeX-rendered math captions
- Developed AngularJS front-end leveraging YouTube API · Exposed Django REST API + PostgreSQL

Handshake

connecting people online through physical handshakes

October 2015

- Developed hardware prototype for smart watches wearers to shake hands and connect online.
- Allows professionals to easily network at conferences and for students to easily connect with recruiters.
- Implemented RESTful API backend with ASP.NET WebAPI and Microsoft SQL hosted on Azure.
- Won 2nd place in Microsoft Prize category at HackATL, a tech startup hackathon at Emory University

SKILLS

LANGUAGES

FRAMEWORKS
PACKAGING / DEPLOYMENT
CONTINUOUS INTEGRATION
DATABASES
MACHINE LEARNING

IDES / ENVIRONMENTS

GRAPHIC DESIGN / ANIMATION

HUMAN-COMPUTER INTERACTION

Python, JavaScript / TypeScript, C#, Swift, Java, MATLAB, HTML5 / CSS3. Shell

.NET, iOS, Django + REST, Angular, Ionic, NodeJS, Android

Vagrant, Docker, Heroku, Microsoft Azure, Digital Ocean, Gradle Git + Git Flow, Jenkins, Travis CI / CircleCI / Wercker Microsoft SQL Server (T-SQL), PostgreSQL, Redis

hmm-learn, Digital Signal Processing, MATLAB, scikit-learn PyCharm, Visual Studio + ReSharper, IntelliJ IDEA

Sketch (macOS), Adobe (Illustrator, After Effects, Premiere Pro, Photoshop, Audition, InDesign), MAXON Cinema 4D, Octane Render UX Research, UI Design, Study Design (counter-balancing, dual-task, learning effects, etc.), Interview Design, Data Visualization, Statistics